# Schlumberger

### **CURRICULUM VITAE**

Name

### JEROME DE CUYPER

Title

### **Programmer**

**Profile** 

Software developer with strong professional experience delivering scalable web applications using ASP.NET, C#, ASP, PHP, MSSQL, Javascript and Actionscript.

Always strive to write reliable and reusable code, cut development time by creating new tools and focus on the client's needs and requirements.

### **Key Skills**

- 1 year of experience working in the oil and gas industry developing online dynamic production management systems (Con Edison, Angola LNG).
- 8 years of experience delivering dynamic websites using ASP, ASP.NET, Javascript and MVC.
- Experience developing Windows Services and scheduled tasks configuration tools.
- Experience elaborating unit tests and continuous integration processes (NUnit, Watin, CruiseControl.Net).
- Knowledge of mobile application development (iPad, iPhone, Android).
- Professional internship of 6 months working remotely for IBM, Austin, Texas (Java).
- 6 months experience programming graphical application with OpenGL,
  C y C++.

### **Education**

### Master's Degree in Computer Science.

Tecnológico de Monterrey Institute (2009 – 2012).

### Bachelor Degree in Sociology.

Catholic University of Louvain-la-Neuve (1998 – 2002).

# Professional experience 09/2011

### **SPT GROUP**

Consultant.

Con Edison. Pipeline management system for a steam distribution system under New York City.

Angola LNG. Pipeline management system for a gas trunkline system feeding into an LNG facility in Angola.

 Responsible for the design and implementation of the HMI used to assist the operator in daily operational planning and decision making through effective forecasting and monitoring of key operational parameters

# Schlumberger

(ASP.NET, MSSQL).
 Development of an online HMI page editor and of a code library with commonly used functionality (C#).
 Implementation of unit tests and a continuous integration server (CruiseControl.NET).

### 01/2011 - 08/2011

### **GRUPO VALMEX (Stock Market)**

Senior web programmer.

- Development of the brokerage house and corporate website (Drupal, Javascript): highly customizable and multiuser access.
- Development of the online banking portal (C#, MVC, Javascript): secured access to the client's account information.

### 08/2007 - 12/2010

### **GAUDELLI MCW**

Senior web programmer.

- Riviera Maya Travel Agent Program: online e-learning and certification program in five languages (MSSQL, Actionscript, C#).
- Interactive Mexican House of Representatives: simulation software that allows visualizing the seat distribution of all political groups based on precise vote estimations (Actionscript, C#).
- Social networking website for kids: create event based API to allow communication between Actionscript and C# backend.

### 08/2006 to 08/2011

### FINANCIAL INSTITUTION (CONFIDENTIAL)

Junior web programmer.

 Development of web applications to process and assign potential corporate credit card holders to account executives (C#, MSSQL Service Broker, NUnit).

### 01/2005 to 08/2007

### **EXAGONO SOFTWARE**

Junior web programmer.

 Develop software to synchronize industrial balances (Mettler Toledo ID7) with a central database (VB6, sockets).

### **Training**

2012

**SPT GROUP.** Building Competencies Training. Houston TX, USA.

2012

MatrikonOPC. Integration and diagnostics (level 1, 2 y 3). Houston TX, USA.

2008

**Microsoft.** Building COM+ Applications Using Microsoft .NET Enterprise Services. Mexico City, Mexico.

2007

UNAM. Intermediate C# training. Mexico City, Mexico.

# Schlumberger Public

# Schlumberger

### 2006

Training4U. Intermediate Actionscript training. Mexico City, Mexico.

2005

Instituto Politécnico Nacional. Intermediate Java training. Mexico City, Mexico.

### **Key trainings**

### IBM. Austin TX. USA

Remote collaborator.

New plugin for IBM's Tivoli Federated Identity Manager to handle token's attributes through compiled Javascript (WS-Trust, Java, Rhino).

### ITESM. Computer graphics. Mexico City, Mexico Student.

3D track and field game (C++, OpenGL).

### ITESM. Artifical Intelligence. Mexico City, Mexico Student.

Random website filter based on Bayesian probability (C#).

### **Software Proficiency**

- OS: Win 2003 & 2008, Win XP/Vista/7, OpenSuse, centOS, iOS.
- Databases: SQL Server 2000/2005/2008, MySQL.
- Softwares: Visual Studio 2003/2005/2008/2010, Flash CS5, Xcode 4.
- Web servers: IIS 5/6/7, Apache, WebSphere Application Server, Tomcat.
- Frameworks: Code Ignitor, Spring, Spring MVC, Spring.NET, Spring ActionScript, Drupal, Wordpress.
- Programming and markup languages: C/C++, Actionscript, Objective C, ASP, PHP, C#, SQL, J2EE, Javascript, HTML, XML.

### **Contact**

Jerome De Cuyper jcu@sptgroup.com

Tel. +52 (55) 3211 9211 Fax. +52 (55) 3211 9212 Mob. +521 55 1619 8599